Guide to the Susan Olzak Papers SC1299
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Susan Olzak papers
1954-1998
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Olzak, Susan
SC1299
13.5 Linear Feet (9 cartons)
Biographical / Historical
Susan Olzak is Professor of Sociology at Stanford University, where she does research on armed conflict, ethnic violence, collective action, and social movement organizations. Olzak earned a B.A. from the University of Wisconsin in 1969; an M.A. from San Jose State University in 1972; and a Ph.D. in Sociology from Stanford University in 1978.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Susan Olzak, 2016.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists primarily of data and supporting documentation related to the Ethnic Collective Action in Contemporary Urban U.S. project led by Olzak. The project goal was to identify sources of ethnic and racial conflict and protest in urban America from 1954 through 1992. Collection materials are dated from 1954-1998.
United States -- Ethnic relations; United States -- Race relations; Olzak, Susan; Olzak, Susan
- Ethnic Collective Action Records and Data, Accession ARCH-2017-001
  - Ethnic Collective Action, 1954-1972
    - Events, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Events, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Events Non-Events, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Events, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Events, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Non-Events, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Non-Events, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Events, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - First half year Coded Clare Tune, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Non-Events, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Events not in SMSA- not Coded (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Coded Events, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Changes, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Changes, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Changes, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Changes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Non-Events, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Non-Events questionable Events (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Coded completed forms, 1962 Jan 1-May 31 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Income inequality, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Events not Coded, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Raw data from NYT (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Selma voter registration (21), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Warb riot George, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Non-Events, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Non-Events, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Events, 1965 Mar 14 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Events, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Events, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Non-SMSA, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Detroit riot, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Events (continued), 1967 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 1968 Feb (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 1968 Mar (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 1968 Jun (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - N-M Necmas; Watson, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1967-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Non-Events, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Changes, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Events, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Not in SMSA, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - 1969 Dec (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Events, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Non-SMSA Events, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Non-event, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - summaries, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Non-Events, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - untitled (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - 1972 Aug (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Code sheets, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Partial, 1971 Sep-Dec (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - untitled (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Codebook: Events, 1965-1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - CAS Excel master disks (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Coded, 1968 Jan (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - If lost, return to Sociology room 243, 1968 Apr (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - If lost, return to Sociology room 243, 1969 Dec (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - 1968 Jun (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - If lost, return to Sociology room 243, 1969 Oct (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - If lost, return to Sociology room 243, 1968 Mar (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - If lost, return to Sociology room 243, 1968 Feb (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ethnic Collective Action, 1972-1983
    - Non-Events NYT, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Events from NYT [NB still to be revised], 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Non-EV, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - untitled (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - untitled (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - untitled (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Events, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Non-Events, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Events, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - NYT narratives (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Current work, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Non-Events, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Events, 1979 Jan-Sep (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Non-Events (some not in SMSA's) old forms that have been transcribed, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Events to locally check, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - 1979 Feb (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - 1979 Jul (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Coding sheet, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Non-Events, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Photocopies, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Old coding Molly's version, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - 1981 Nov (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - 1982 Aug (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Coding sheet, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Coding sheet, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Stripped code, 1982 Sep (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - 1982 Dec (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - 1983 Jan (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - 1983 Feb (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - 1983 Mar (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Coding sheet, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Non-Events, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Ethnic Collective Action, 1982-1990
    - Coding sheet, 1983 Apr (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Stripped code, 1983 Jun (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Stripped code, 1983 Jul (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Stripped code, 1983 Sep (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - NYT, 1983 Oct (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - NYT, 1983 Nov (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Coding sheet, 1983 Dec (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Coding sheet, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - untitled (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Coding sheet (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Coding sheet, 1984 Jan (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - NYT, 1984 Apr (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Stripped code, 1984 May (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Stripped code, 1984 Jun (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - NYT, 1984 Aug (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Stripped code, 1984 Sep (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Stripped code, 1984 Oct (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - 1984 Nov (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Stripped code, 1984 Dec (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Coding sheet, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Coding sheet, 1985 Dec (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - untitled (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Events - Erica, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Events, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - untitled (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - untitled (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Events, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Proquest, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Coded Events (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Necmas, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - WIATT, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - NYT, 1987 Aug (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Stripped code, 1987 Sep (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Worksheet for stripped code, 1987 Nov (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Coding sheet, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Non-Events, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - DEWI Project Events, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Coding sheet, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Events, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Code sheet, 1987 Dec (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Stripped code, 1988 Mar (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - NYT, 1988 Jun (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Stripped code, 1989 Jan (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - NYT, 1989 Feb (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - NYT, 1989 Apr (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Stripped code, 1989 Jun (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Stripped code, 1989 Jul (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Stripped code, 1989 Aug (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Stripped code, 1989 Sep (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Stripped code, 1989 Oct (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - 1989 Dec (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Stripped code, 1990 Jan (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - 1990 Feb (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Ethnic Collective Action, 1990-1998
    - Stripped code, 1990 Jun (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - NYT, 1990 Jul (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Stripped code, 1990 Aug (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Stripped code, 1990 Mar (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Stripped code, 1990 Sep (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Stripped code, 1990 Oct (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - NYT, 1990 Dec (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Stripped code, 1990 May (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Stripped code, 1991 Jan (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Stripped code, 1991 Feb (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Stripped code, 1991 Mar (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - NYT, 1991 Apr (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Stripped code, 1991 May (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - NYT, 1991 Jun (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Stripped code, 1991 Jul (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Events, 1991 Aug (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Stripped code, 1991 Sep (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Copies, 1991 Oct (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Stripped code, 1991 Nov (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Completely Coded, 1991 Dec (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Stripped code, 1992 Sep (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Code sheet, 1993 Feb (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Stripped code, 1993 Mar (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Stripped code, 1993 Apr (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Articles, 1993 May (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Stripped code, 1993 Jun (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Code sheet Stripped code, 1993 Oct (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - completely Coded, 1993 Nov (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - NYT, 1993 Nov (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Stripped code, 1993 Dec (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Coding sheet, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - LA Race Riot, 1992 Apr 29-30 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Events, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Stripped code, 1994 Jul (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Stripped code, 1994 Jan (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Stripped code, 1994 Feb (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Stripped code, 1994 May (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Stripped code, 1994 Aug (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Stripped code NYT, 1994 Sep (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Stripped code, 1994 Oct (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Stripped code, 1994 Nov (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Code sheet Stripped code, 1994 Dec (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Jan (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Feb (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Apr (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Stripped code NYT, 1995 May (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Riots, 1968-1991
    - Code sheet Stripped code, 1995 Jun (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Jul (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Aug (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Sep (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Oct (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Nov (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Stripped code, 1995 Dec (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Busing Events n=163, 1992 Feb 11 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - the SAS system, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - SAS system, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Coding sheet, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Coding sheet, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Coding sheet, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Events, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Photocopies, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - SMSAS, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - SMSAS, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Coding sheet, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - SAS system, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Coding sheet, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Coding sheet, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - riots (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Coding sheet, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Coding sheet, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Coding sheet, 1958 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Coding sheet, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Coding sheet, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Coding sheet, 1961 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Coding sheet, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Coding sheet, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - 1977 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - 1981 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - 1983 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - DBASE Coding sheet, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - 1985 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - 1986 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - 1987 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - 1988 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - 1989 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - 1990 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - 1991 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - 1992 (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Codebook: Events, 1877-1914 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Events, 1877-1914 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Is it an event? Guide, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Ethnic mobilization project codebook for coding ethnic collective Events (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Data
    - Cornell Department of Sociology file (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - City Level - Ethnic Collective Action (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Coding material (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Coding material (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Coding material (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Collective acts - Quebec (Box 9, Folder 6)